Yuan Yao

POSTAL ADDRESS

Dept. of Computer Science and Technology Xianlin Campus, Nanjing University 163 Xianlin Avenue, Nanjing, China 210046

CONTACT INFO

Email: yyao@smail.nju.edu.cn Homepage: http://moon.nju.edu.cn/~YuanYao

SHORT BIOGRAPHY

Yuan Yao is an assistant professor within the State Key Lab for Novel Software and Technology, Department of Computer Science and Technology, Nanjing University. Before that, he received his Ph.D. degree at the same department in September 2015 supervised by Prof. Feng Xu and Prof. Jian Lu. His research interest lies in data mining and software technology.

EDUCATION

2011.09 - 2015.09: PhD Student, Department of Computer Science and Technology, Nanjing University

2012.09 - 2013.03: Research Intern at Department of Computer Science, North Carolina State University (Supervisor: Prof. Tao Xie)

2009.09 - $2011.07{:}$ Graduate student, Department of Computer Science and Technology, Nanjing University

2005.09 - 2009.06: B.Sc., Department of Computer Science and Technology, Nanjing University

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2015.10 - 2016.04: Research Staff Member, Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd

2016.05 - present: Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science and Technology, Nanjing University

HONORS AND AWARDS

IBM scholarship for Excellent Graduate Students, 2014

KDD Student Travel Award, 2014

'Data Mining Reveals the Secret to Getting Good Answers', MIT Technology Review

National Scholarship, 2013

Nanrui scholarship for Excellent Graduate Students, 2012

Guorui scholarship for Excellent Graduate Students, 2011

1st Grade Public Scholarship, 2008

2nd Grade Public Scholarship, 2007

 3^{rd} Grade Public Scholarship, 2006

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Journal Publications

- 1. Yuan Yao, Hanghang Tong, Tao Xie, Leman Akoglu, Feng Xu, Jian Lu, Detecting High-quality Posts in Community Question Answering Sites. Information Sciences, 2015 (CCF RANK B).
- 2. Yuan Yao, Hanghang Tong, Xifeng Yan, Feng Xu, Jian Lu, Multi-Aspect+ Transitivity+ Bias: An Integral Trust Inference Model, IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering, 2014 (CCF RANK A).
- 3. Yuan Yao, Feng Xu, Yongli Ren, Hanghang Tong, Jian Lu, SelfTrust: Leveraging Self-Assessment for Trust Inference in Internetware, SCIENCE CHINA Information Sciences, 2013 (CCF RANK B).

Conference Publications

- 1. Liangyue Li, Yuan Yao, Jie Tang, Wei Fan, Hanghang Tong, QUINT: On Query-Specific Optimal Networks, KDD 2016 (CCF RANK A).
- 2. Jingwei Xu, Yuan Yao, Hanghang Tong, Xianping Tao, Jian Lu, Ice-Breaking: Mitigating Cold-Start Recommendation Problem by Rating Comparison, IJCAI 2015. (CCF RANK A)

- 3. Yuan Yao, Hanghang Tong, Guo Yan, Feng Xu, Xiang Zhang, Boleslaw Szymanski, Jian Lu, Dual-Regularized One-Class Collaborative Filtering, CIKM'14, 2014 (CCF RANK B).
- 4. Yuan Yao, Hanghang Tong, Feng Xu, Jian Lu, Predicting Long-Term Impact of CQA Posts: A Comprehensive Viewpoint, KDD'14, 2014 (CCF RANK A).
- 5. Yuan Yao, Hanghang Tong, Xifeng Yan, Feng Xu, Jian Lu, MATRI: A Multi-Aspect and Transitive Trust Inference Model, WWW'13, 2013 (CCF RANK A).

PRESENTATIONS

- 1. "Comparing Linkage Graph and Activity Graph of Online Social Networks", paper delivered at 3rd International Conference on Social Informatics (SocInfo), 6 8 October, 2011.
- 2. "PatTrust: A Pattern-based Evaluation Approach for Trust and Distrust in Internetware", paper delivered at 3rd Asia-Pacific Symposium on Internetware (Internetware), 1 2 December, 2011.
- "Subgraph Extraction for Trust Inference in Social Networks", paper delivered at the IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining (ASONAM), 26 - 29 August, 2012.
- 4. "MATRI: A Multi-Aspect and Transitive Trust Inference Model", paper delivered at the 22nd International World Wide Web Conference (WWW), 13 17 May, 2013.
- "Joint Voting Prediction for Questions and Answers in CQA", paper delivered at the IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining (ASONAM), 17 - 20 August, 2014.
- "Predicting Long-Term Impact of CQA Posts: A Comprehensive Viewpoint" paper delivered at the 20th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 24 - 27 August, 2014.
- 7. "Dual-Regularized One-Class Collaborative Filtering" paper delivered at the 23rd ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 3 7 November, 2014.

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

PC Member: CIKM 2015, IJCAI 2015 -2016, ASONAM 2016, DMCCI 2011